Guardian of the Forest
Check out this explosion of art, haha!
Hahaha! Something exploded, alright!
What did you say?!
Nothing...
Get out of here now...
That wasn't me!
I said, get out!
W-what was that?!
V-Vance!
Aaah!
Hahaha! A monster?!
You expect us to believe that?!
We really saw it, you guys!
It had a long neck, sharp teeth, and it even said,
"Get out of this forest!" It spoke to us!!!
The monster could even talk?
There's no way.
You better hurry home today so you don't see it again!
I swear it's true!
Making up stories about monsters?
Even I could come up with something more believable than that.
You mean... like robots from space?
Crest?!
W-what do you mean by robots, Crest?
Y-yeah, w-what are you talking about?
It seems like strange things happen quite often in this town.
Don't you think it might be too early to dismiss Vance's story as just a tall tale?
There's been a series of accidents taking place at the new highway being constructed in the north of Mowtown.
All the workers on-site said the exact same thing.
That a giant monster appeared from within the fog.
What?!
Don't you think it's worth checking out?
Waaah!!
You mean to tell me there's monsters like that here on Earth?!
There weren't any monsters like that back on planet Machina!
Don't worry. It's only a movie, you guys.
Of course. I knew it wasn't real.
Blue Cop!
Jun.
Let's go monster hunting!
What?! Monster?!
You're kidding, right?!
Huh?
Go hunt them yourself!
What's going on?
Beats me.
So you think the monster behind the rumors could actually be a Metal Cardbot?
That does seem to be the most likely story.
I wonder how much Crest knows about the Metal Cardbots?
That's been bothering me too.
But we need to focus on figuring out who this monster is first.
Okay, we're here.
Crest!
Hey guys. I was waiting for you.
Yeah. Let's go.
He's not a very good artist.
Looks just like Vance.
Be careful, master.
Is it okay to be here without permission?
Construction has been suspended since the accidents. All that remains is...
Waah!
Wildlife. Like that raccoon.
There's a lot of animals around here.
There used to be a lot around the car center too.
They disappeared as the city continued to be developed.
Look, over there!
Is that a footprint?
It's huge!
It couldn't belong to an animal.
About 12 meters in height.
Bigger than the robot we saw last time.
We can't say for sure it was a robot!
Yeah! It could be part of a conspiracy trying to cover up what's going on!
What kind of conspiracy theory is that?
Watch out, Jun. Something's close.
Get out now!
What's that?
Get out right now!
Which way did that come from?!
Get out of this forest...
...RIGHT NOW!!
It's a monster!!
Who's there?!
An excavator?
Careful, Jun. That's...
Didn't you hear me?! I said, GET OUT!
Waah!!
Let's hide under there!
!
Uncle Edo, hurry up!
I can't fit!
That's what happens when you have all those muscles!
Over there!
Phew, I'm safe.
I told you to get out of here!
!
Uncle Edo!
Uncle!
The monster turned out to be a Metal Cardbot after all.
What do I do? I can't summon them with Crest around.
Let go of him!
Wait a moment, Crest!
Hey!
Why are you chasing people away?
I don't like humans.
What did we do?
You really don't know?
It's because you're all destroying the forests.
Every time the humans expand the roads, creatures of the forest lose their home.
That's why I-
Why you pretended to be a monster to chase people out and to destroy the construction site?
Yeah. Something wrong with that?
Acting like a guardian of the forest...
While using violence to suppress others?
What's the difference between that and what the humans you hate are doing?
Shut up!
Waah!
Uncle Edo!
Do you even know... how many forest creatures have been sacrificed...
all because of humans?!
Crest!
Don't worry about me. Just run!
I know you wouldn't run if it were me lying there!
Jun? Are you going to show him?!
The secret of the Metal Cardbots?
Metal Cardbot, pick-
Is that...
Wild Guardy!
All of you, get out of here.
Guys! Please take care of Crest!
Got it!
Crest, are you okay?!
I-I think I can walk...
Hold on tight!
And what about me, guys?...
Waah!
You?
You dare injure a human being?
You are a disgrace to the Metal Cardbots!
Oh!
Master Crest!
How did this happen?!
That didn't go... as well as I hoped...
Crest!
Oh!
Master Crest, sir!
I can't see anything!
Be prepared, Dexter.
I, Wild Guardy, will take you down!
Hold on!
If he hates humans that much, he won't open up to us no matter what we do!
Please, leave it to us!
Us?
Metal Breath, pickup!
Blue Cop, setup!
Out of my way, Blue Cop! Dexter is mine to punish.
Wild Guardy, can't you see? That won't solve anything.
That's none of my concern.
That heap of scrap hurt my friend!
What?!
You can't run away from me!
Stop it!
I have no intention of listening to you!
Mega Ambler, it's your turn!
I'll leave this to you, Mega Ambler!
Got it!
You're going to have to settle for me.
Don't be ridiculous!
!
Where... am I?
Huh?
Here! Blue Cop!
Dexter! Stop!
Stop following me!
Blue Cop! Are you alright?
That was a powerful attack.
Blue Cop! Let's use the Infinity Force Break to end this right now!
Infinity Force Break?
Infinity...
Force...
Break!!
But... if we use it here, the tunnel could collapse.
But...
Dexter is gone!
Let's go after him!
Woah, look out!
What's this?